# **OMKAR S. SHETKAR**

omishetkar@gmail.com 📱 9833342066 📍 Mumbai / Hyd 🗓 https://www.linkedin.com/in/dr-omkar-shetkar-a415b316a/

An accomplished HR professional with 14+ years of experience in managing end to end human resources operations including recruiting, talent acquisition, screening, interview scheduling, HR-MIS management, employee grievance management and performance management across shipping, logistics, information technology and insurance verticals.

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE / SKILLS / HRMS SOFTWARE

- End-to-End HR Mgmt
- Recruitment
- Attendance & Leave Mgmt
- BambooHR

- HR Operations
- Induction/Training
- Payroll Processing
- DarwinBox

- Employee Grievance
- Exit Formalities
- Audit Policies & Compliance
- GoBetter/Betterplace

### **CAREER HISTORY**

Aug'2024 - Till Date	Regional HR / Asst Manager-HRBP	Rentokil PCI (Acquired HiCare Services Pvt Ltd)
Dec'2022 - Jul'2024	Regional HR / TA Manager	HiCare Services Pvt Ltd, Mumbai & Pune

### **Key Deliverables:**

### **Talent Acquisitions:**

- Handling recruitments of on-roll & off-roll feet on street employees(Blue-collar staff).
- Ensuring trained availability of trained manpower within 15 days of manpower requisition.
- On-boarding new joinees as per the pre-define on-boarding process.
- Preparing various sources of hiring such as Naukri, consultants, own referrals, newspaper ads, etc.

# **Retention & Performance Orientation:**

- Handling retention of off-roll as well as on-roll employees.
- Visiting all Off-roll employees in the region and meeting them once in 15 days.
- Training and career progression of employees in the region.
- Managing retention of hi-potential employees and management trainees.
- Managing region R&R on a monthly basis.
- Handling Performance management through monthly incentives and Performance Improvement Plans.

# **Data Reconciliation:**

- Weekly reconciliation of manpower of Off-roll and on-roll employees
- Reconcile the employee data with Ops team
- Managing HRMS records

# Payroll:

- Maintaining daily attendance of Off-roll and On-roll employees.
- Providing inputs for payroll processing and Daily allowances
- Completing exit formalities of all exiting employees in terms of asset recovery, advance recoveries, etc.
- Maintaining correct records of all exits and ensure F&F is paid within 45 days

# **HR Compliances:**

• Ensuring all HR Compliances are in order for the region in terms of employment exchange, Profession tax, client audits, etc.

Mar' 2022 - Nov' 2022 Talent Acquisition Manager BellPlus Media Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad

# **Key Deliverables:**

• Entire range of HR activities covering - recruitment, selection, induction, wages & salary administration, grievance handling, discipline, welfare schemes etc. to build and retain a committed workforce.

- Preparation of offer letters, salary annexures and updated information in HR Database.
- Performing employee exit formalities including scheduling and coordinating in exit interviews and other exit formalities organized by the HR manager.
- Organized person/group meeting with employees regularly to understand, address, and resolve the issues, concerns, opinions and feedback.
- Designed policies/procedures and updated the same to employees regularly also responded to issues related to policies/procedures by utilizing internal communication channels.

# Jan 2020 – Jan 2022 HR & Operations Manager Ansec HR Services Ltd., Mumbai

# **Key Deliverables:**

- Carried out a wide range of operations including recruitment activities of Security Guards, Supervisors, Security
  Officer, etc; joining formalities, performance appraisal management, attendance/absence management,
  employee engagement, and discipline/grievance
- Steered employee engagement operations within the team and coaching on duties/responsibilities in adherence to organisational rules
- Supervised/mentored the team and enhancing the team performance by setting up go goals and objectives
- Performed health/safety assessments, subsequent investigations, preparing incident reports and updating same to the health & safety committees
- Key involvement in performing risk assessments, site evaluations and generating monthly performance reports and billing schedules

# April 2018 - Dec 2019 Freelancer - HR Consultant Sept 2017 - March 2018 Recruitment and Development Manager @ Kotak Mahindra Life Insurance Apr 2013 - Sept 2017 Human Resources Executive @ Lumen21 Infoserv India Pvt., Ltd. May 2012 - Sept 2012 Human Resources Assistant @ United Gaskets & Components Pvt., Ltd. Aug 2010 - June 2011 Human Resources Officer @ Maersk India Pvt., Ltd.

### **Overall Key Deliverables:**

- Managed the entire life cycle of employees recruitment, L&D till exit.
- Played a vital role in the preparation of offer letters, salary annexures, background verification operations and updated information in HR software also managed training & induction operations such as scheduling training calendar, and organizing training programs for new employees regularly
- Organized person/group meeting with employees regularly to understand, address, and resolve the issues, concerns, opinions and feedback
- Designed policies/procedures and updated same to employees regularly also responded to issues related to policies/procedures by utilizing internal communication channels
- Carried out US Recruitment operations like shortlisting of resumes using dice.com, craigslist.com and LinkedIn

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Master of Business Administration in Human Resources, IBSAR, TMU (Pune)
 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, Mumbai University, India.

# **Achievements:**

- Best Performer Award below 6 months RDMs from Kotak Life Insurance
- Hicare Performance Delivered Feb 2023
- Hicare Performance Delivered July 2023